Hey guys, welcome to the last topic of MITRE, the impact section.
So in this video, we are going to discuss about the shadow copies in the Windows mission.
So if you see, before deploying the ransomware, before encrypting a machine, what the
protectors will do, okay.
So let us say you have, you have successfully compromised one of our organization.
And the data in the organization is really important, right?
Anyway, you are going to exfiltrate the data into the cloud application and you are going
to encrypt all the important files and folders present inside the machine.
So how the organization will pay their ransom amount for you?
They need their data, right?
They need their data back and the data should not be in an encrypted format.
So if let us say, you have successfully encrypted all the data, okay.
But the organization already have the backup file in another server or a cloud platform.
They can rebuild the machine.
Once you encrypted the machine, they can easily rebuild the machine with the backup files.
They have a backup files, they don't need to pay their ransom amount to you because they
have a backup file.
They can easily backup all the files inside, uh, into the Windows mission.
So the exfiltration, you are exfilted the exfilted the, uh, since you data, that is one
of the thing.
But what organization will think, uh, the system is also encrypted and, uh, to decrypt
the data, you will be asking some money as a hacker, as a ransomware, that, uh, you will
be going to ask some money to provide a description key, uh, sorry, decryption key to the organization.
And uh, what organization will think?
So they have, they already have a backup files.
So why they need to pay the money for you, right?
So they can easily rebuild the machine, uh, reinstall the windows and they can easily
backup all the files.
Right?
So this, there is a problem for, uh, a ransomware detector, uh, so there is one solution
for, uh, hackers, so every backup files, okay.
So if windows sending any backup files, uh, to the cloud, we will be calling it as a shadow
copies.
So the shadow copies is nothing but the shadow copy file only knows which file
and folders belongs to which directory, basically, okay.
So it's basically like a, uh, blueprint of the entire, uh, file system inside your
windows machine.
So the shadow copies know which file and which, uh, folders will be sitting in, see,
see directory or a D directory or a E directory or anything.
So if you deleted the shadow copy from the machine, so still, if you have a backup file,
your computer would not be able to backup all the files, uh, from the cloud or any server
platforms, okay.
So the backup file is a, the shadow copy file is a blueprint of all the files present inside
the windows machine.
So if you deleted the shadow copies, okay, so if you deleted the shadow copy of a machine,
so if you have a backup file also, you can't able to recover, uh, recover the file inside
the host, okay, because the blueprint has been deleted.
The windows doesn't know where to keep this file, uh, inside the machine, okay.
So shadow copies are, uh, most important thing, uh, they will do when they are, uh,
when they are targeting, uh, around somewhere inside the machine, okay.
So you can see adversaries may delete or remove the built-in data, turn off services designed
to aid off recovery of a character's, this character system.
So if the system was corrupted, if the system was encrypted or corrupted, uh, corrupted.
So if you need to take a backup from your, uh, server or a cloud platform, the shadow
copies will be one of the important thing, uh, to do a backup.
So if you do not have a shadow copies, your system could not able to recover the data from
the cloud and the system could not know which files, which files, uh, needs to keep in
which folder or which, uh, files belongs to which directory, okay.
So we are going to delete a blueprint, uh, the entire blueprint, uh, of the file system.
So basically, uh, we'll, we'll say, okay.
So deleting the where volume shadow copies is one of the primary target of the threat
factors.
If they, if they need to install the ransomware inside the environment, if they need to encrypt
the data inside the organization, okay, before encrypting the data, they, their target is
like, they need to delete all the backup related things.
The organization should not go for a backup so that they'll be deleting the shadow copies,
okay.
So that was an easy thing, uh, deleting the shadow copies, okay.
So already we, we, we, we just, uh, took the impact and, uh, the simple command is like
VSS, uh, VSS are been delete shadows, okay.
Let me list, uh, the shadow of VSS, I mean, list shadows.
So my system do not have a, uh, shadow copies, let me, so if you, so, if you see,
you don't have a correct permission to run this command.
Let me run this is an administrator format, so no item phone, uh, satisfy the query because
I do not have any kind of recovery, uh, software for any kind of recovery, uh, in recovery,
uh, programs that was installed to take a back of, uh, about my mission.
So this is the test mission.
I didn't did that, uh, but the organization missions will be take a backup every day, uh,
at the particular time, okay.
So deleting the val, valing shadow copies is one of the important thing, uh, for a threat
type does, okay.
So here it's nothing but VSS admin, it's one of, uh, the, uh, command line features.
So administrator command line tool, okay.
So you just need to give the parameter, uh, like delete shadows, okay.
So it will delete the shadow copy from the C directory.
So if you, you, this command, yes, it's, uh, delete.
I think I, uh, yeah, command or site, if you, you this command, it will delete the shadow
copies.
Okay.
If you, if you want to delete all the shadow copies, uh, from the mission, you can simply
type all, okay.
It will delete all the shadow copies, okay.
By deleting the shadow copies, your system could not able to take a backup from the, uh,
cloud platform or any, uh, any kind of servers, uh, if it, if it's, it's the system
was corrupted.
Okay.
So the organization, uh, the organization will be blank, because they have deleted the shadows.
They can't able to take a backup, they, they do not, they, they are like blank.
They, needs to pay the amount to you and they need to take a key from your, uh, key from
you.
Right.
Uh, yeah, let's, uh, yeah, this is the scenario.
So once they, once the, once the detector has a tactics to install the ransomware inside the
environment, okay.
I hope you have a clear understanding about this, uh, we'll connect you guys in a next
video with WMI-V. Okay.